<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Randomness Challenge</name>
    <directory>randomness challenge</directory>
    <id>2765647569</id>
    <description>I find that I tend to take the same path on most of my normal playthroughs. This mod tries to mix that up with random paths and characters.

There's over 50 paths, including:
[list]
    [*]Mom
    [*]Mom -&gt; It Lives
    [*]Mom -&gt; It Lives -&gt; Isaac
    [*]Mom -&gt; It Lives -&gt; Isaac -&gt; Blue Baby
    [*]Mom -&gt; It Lives -&gt; Isaac -&gt; Mega Satan
    [*]Mom -&gt; Mother
    [*]Mom -&gt; Mother -&gt; Hush
    [*]Mom -&gt; Mother -&gt; Hush -&gt; Satan
    [*]Mom -&gt; Mother -&gt; Hush -&gt; Satan -&gt; The Lamb
    [*]Mom -&gt; Mother -&gt; Hush -&gt; Satan -&gt; The Lamb -&gt; Delirium
    [*]Ascent -&gt; The Beast
[/list]

You can tap the map button to show your path.

None of the paths go past Mega Satan or The Beast, but if you use a mod like AlwaysVoid then you can continue on after Mega Satan if you want.

I haven't seen a random Void portal show up in a custom challenge recently, but if one does then you can always choose to end your run by fighting Delirium.

Right now, trapdoors spawn in the center of the room rather than their normal positions. I might leave this or change it. I haven't made up my mind yet. I like that it feels a bit different.

If relevant: The polaroid and negative aren't required. Knife pieces 1 and 2 are required. Key pieces 1 and 2 will be spawned at the start of your run.

There's 5 challenges that are based around character selection.

[b][u]Randomness Challenge[/u][/b]

This challenge will start you with a random character.
[olist]
    [*]Isaac
    [*]Maggy
    [*]Cain
    [*]Judas
    [*]Blue Baby
    [*]Eve
    [*]Samson
    [*]Azazel
    [*]Lazarus
    [*]The Lost
    [*]Lilith
    [*]Keeper
    [*]Apollyon
    [*]The Forgotten
    [*]Bethany
    [*]Jacob and Esau
[/olist]

If you really want to start with a specific character then you can press the corresponding number(s) on your keyboard when starting the challenge. For example:
[list]
    [*]1 = Isaac
    [*]0 = 10 = The Lost
    [*]0 + 1 = 11 = Lilith
[/list]

[b][u]Randomness Challenge (Tainted)[/u][/b]

This challenge will start you with a random tainted character from the list above.

[b][u]Randomness Challenge (Eden)[/u][/b]

Eden is already pretty random.

[b][u]Randomness Challenge (T-Eden)[/u][/b]

Tainted Eden is even more random.

[b][u]Randomness Challenge (Trainer)[/u][/b]

This challenge starts you as Isaac with TMTRAINER. It's basically the DELETE THIS challenge with a custom path.</description>
    <version>1.9</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Challenges"/>
</metadata>
